Well, David Gres also spoke to the
congressional uh committees. Is that
what you're talking about?
>> Yes.
>> That that is another way to protect
yourself.
>> Yes. Is you you reach out to the people
who were supposed to have oversight
authority over this kind of thing. So,
if you're not getting any satisfaction
or you can't, you know, get people to
take you seriously, reach out to the
House and Senate uh armed services
committees. They'll take you seriously.
I think he went through all the steps,
the proper steps, but
>> Yes, he did. He He went to the inspector
general. He went to the general counsel
and nobody would listen to him.
>> I see. Wow. Yeah. Um, so here's say
another question here for you from Tony.
In light of what you went through, would
you recommend a career in the CIA?
>> As crazy as it might sound,
I would have to say yes.
>> Wow.
>> And I'll tell you why.
I loved every minute that I was in the
CIA. I went to 72 countries.
I met with kings and presidents and
prime ministers. I did the coolest stuff
you could imagine that I have to keep
secret until I, you know, am laid in my
grave.
And one of the things that an old-timer
told me that is apppropo of this
question is once you get to around the
10-year mark in your career, you're
going to realize that you've been
promoted into a position of authority,
and for a lot of people, their their
careers really take off at year 10.
There are a lot of things that I don't
like about the CIA. are a lot of things
I want to see changed. But really, look,
I'm a realist. The only way you can
change them is from inside.
>> And so, keep your moral scruples about
you. You know, know right from wrong in
your gut when you go in because they're
not going to teach you right from wrong.
You have to know it yourself
>> and have a great career.
>> Wow. Wow. That's really something. So I
remember I believe that you you watched
what you thought was a war crime and you
>> Yeah.
>> Right away crime.
>> In more ways more ways than the water
boarding. And you know how the water
boarding, you know, basically works is
we're all afraid of drowning. You know,
I mean, that's really what it boils down
to.
>> And in the case of Abu Zuba, they
actually did drown him
>> and his heart stopped and they had to
revive him just so that he could be
tortured more.
>> Yeah. God,
>> it's sick.
>> And of course, you know, when torture is
not really that good at people will say
anything to stop it basically.
>> I mean, how effective is torture really?
I mean, have they done how
>> it's not and that's been that has been
conclusively proven by both the American
Psychological Association and the
American Psychiatric Association. It
just simply doesn't work.
>> Now, you just mentioned his name. That
was someone you knew very well, right?
>> The one they revived. How do you say his
name again?
>> Abu Zabeda.
>> Yeah.
>> I captured Abu Zabeda.
>> And I've gone on record for the last 10
years saying that Abu Zubeda should be
released from Guantanamo immediately and
allowed to uh to resettle in a third
country. We have never charged him with
a crime. And in fact, the information
that uh that we used to uh to
kidnap him and torture him was faulty.
He was not the number three in al-Qaeda.
In fact, he had never even joined
al-Qaeda.
So what we thought, you know, was
conclusive evidence of his guilt of
terrorism was just a lie.
>> Just like someone being falsely charged
with murder, basically.
>> Exactly.
>> Wow. That's amazing.
>> Yeah. Just like murder. And you know,
since 1976, when the death penalty was
reinstated by the Supreme Court, more
than 200 people who had been on death
row have been released because DNA
evidence has conclusively proven them to
be innocent.
>> 200 people
>> were scheduled to be executed that were
completely innocent.
>> It's not acceptable.
>> Yeah. Yeah. There's no way to I mean
someday we may have that ability to
really really know the truth when
someone is telling it. I don't even know
if that would affect our rights or
whatever, but I don't even know you know
if that could even work eventually. But
uh I want to thank you so much. It's
been a real pleasure. Can you please
talk a little bit about the YouTube
channel you have?
>> Oh yeah. Thank you. Uh well I do a
couple of different things. I've got um
I've got a podcast uh that's on YouTube
called Deep Focus with John Kuryaku. I
try to interview uh as many relevant
news makers as I can and um and I've got
a show called CIA Declassified that runs
on an online platform called Unified
Television. UFYD
Unified Television. And what we do is we
look at historic events like the
overthrow of the Iranian government in
1953, the overthrow of the Chilean
government in 73,
MK Ultra, UFOs. Um, and we try to use
declassified CIA documents to shed light
on these on these issues.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah, it's a fun show. We're we're in
season two already and again it's it's
called CIA Declassified and it's at
Unified Television UN I FYD.
>> Wow. Great. Well, I I just have to
mention this the release the recent
re-release of and I don't think it's
that many more documents of the JFK,
>> right?
>> Uh I just wondered what you thought of
that. I know they were unredacted and I
know some social security numbers showed
up from some living
>> and they identified some CIA sources.
There were two blockbuster um uh memos
that were released in that trunch and
there are still several thousand pages
that that are due to be released. But
the two big things were
um
uh James Angleton, the deputy director
of the CIA for counter intelligence,
ordered the CIA in 1963
to recruit Lee Harvey Oswald as a
source. People have long believed that
that was the case. The CIA always denied
it. And now we've learned that they've
been lying for 62 years. So, this is
like it seems like that's a bombshell.
>> That is a bombshell.
>> There's another bombshell. Uh there was
a an army intelligence officer named
Underh Hill um who had highlevel CIA
friends. These friends, he alleged that
these friends told him that they had
been responsible for killing Kennedy. In
a panic, he got in the car and drove to
his mother's house in New Jersey and
told her. She later said that he was
very upset when he told her he drove
back to Washington and then was found
dead in his apartment of a gunshot
wound. They said they ruled it a
suicide, but the gunshot wound was to
the back of his head.
>> Typically doesn't happen. Uh let's see.
>> Oh,
>> sorry. Go right ahead.
>> Well, there's a question for you, but uh
>> yeah, thank you for that. That's that I
I'm starting this hundred
uh hundred city year-long round the
world speaking tour. I've already done
speeches in Belfast, Dublin, and
Manchester. I'm going back to Scotland
and Northern England in a couple of
weeks. Um but we're going to be here in
the United States and in Canada and then
we go to Australia and New Zealand, then
continental Europe, the Persian Gulf,
and East Asia. You can find information
at tigerslanestudio.com.
>> John, I'm going to ask you if you would
take the time to email me all these
links so I can put them in the show
notes for everybody to see.
>> I sure will.
>> And again, for everyone that's uh
watching right now, this YouTube um at
the very end you'll see the video pop up
and that will be the interview that you
and I did back in 2007.
>> Oh, terrific.
>> Yeah. Well, it's been a real pleasure,
John, as always. It's always uh great to
talk to you and I again I I think you're
a hero for doing what you did. I think
um it needed to be done and you know
because who knows where how carried away
that could have gotten.
>> Yeah, thank you.
>> And uh sorry you had to suffer for it,
but uh I'm glad you're doing well now.
>> Thanks so much. It's good to see you
again. It's been a long time. All right.
So, everyone, next week I'm going to be
in I will be uh in California leaving
tomorrow and going to be at the
conference and also our show on next
Tuesday is with Professor Ted Peters and
he is a professor who speaks on the UFO
topic and summer courses at Berkeley.
So, thanks everyone and remember to keep
your eyes to the sky.
Heat.
[Music]